(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-09-28T23:14:48.362925",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆様、本日は轟はじめ生誕祭2025にお越しくださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to the Todoroki Hajime Birthday Celebration 2025 today!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the start of the show, we have some requests and information for you.
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、生配信部分もございますので、いっぱいコメントして盛り上げてください！
This stream includes some pre-recorded segments, but there are also live portions, so please leave lots of comments and cheer me on!
もりもりも見えてるんですけど、うんちょ、うんちょ、番長。
I can see you all super clearly! Uncho, uncho, Bancho!
きゃー！きちゃ！おー！きちゃ！おー！こんにちは。ありがとうございます。
Yay! "It's here!" Oh, "It's starting!" Hello! Thank you so much!
テレビやパソコン、スマートフォンの前での飲食は可能ですが、キーボードにこぼさないようにお気をつけください。
Eating and drinking in front of your TV, PC, or smartphone is allowed, but please be careful not to spill on your keyboard!
当配信のハッシュタグは「#轟はじめ生誕祭2025」です。SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
The hashtag for this stream is #TodorokiHajimeSeitansai2025. Please post a lot on SNS!
開演中、パソコンやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影、大歓迎です。たくさんポストして盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。
Taking photos with your PC or smartphone during the show is highly encouraged! I'd love it if you posted them to hype things up.
それでは、開演までしばらくお待ちください。
Well then, please wait a little longer until the show starts!
皆様、本日は轟はじめ生誕祭2025にお越しくださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to the Todoroki Hajime Birthday Celebration 2025 today!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the start of the show, we have some requests and information for you.
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、生配信部分もございますので、いっぱいコメントして、くれるとすごく嬉しいです。
This stream includes some pre-recorded segments, but there are also live portions, so I'd be super happy if you left lots of comments!
じょわじょわ。二周目助かる。わくわく。二回目。いいだろ二回言っても。ありがとね。
Getting hyped! "Glad to hear it a second time!" "Exciting!" Yes, a second time! Nothing wrong with saying it twice, right? Thank you!
テレビやパソコン、スマートフォンの前での飲食は可能ですが、キーボードにこぼさないようお気をつけください。
Eating and drinking in front of your TV, PC, or smartphone is allowed, but please be careful not to spill on your keyboard!
当配信のハッシュタグは「#轟はじめ生誕祭2025」です。SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
The hashtag for this stream is #TodorokiHajimeSeitansai2025. Please post a lot on SNS!
開演中、パソコンやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影も大歓迎なので、いっぱい、いっぱいポストしてください！
Taking photos with your PC or smartphone during the show is highly welcomed, so please post lots and lots!
それでは、開演までしばらく、もうちょっとお待ちください。
Well then, please wait a little, just a bit longer, until the show starts!
KAMIKAZE
作詞・作曲：マサ
Lyrics & Composition: Masa
言っとくが
I'm telling you,
謝っても無駄
it's no use apologizing.
何がしたいか分からん
I don't know what you want to do.
もううんざりだ
I'm already sick of it.
馬鹿馬鹿だ全く
How ridiculous, really.
あー 息苦しい世界だわ
Ah, what a suffocating world.
1 2 3からカウンター
Counter from 1, 2, 3,
シャイなバーテン ゾンビに頼んだ
I asked the shy bartender zombie.
まやかし あたしのノスタルジア
A deceptive nostalgia of mine,
10年モノでスピットアウト
spit out as a ten-year aged vintage.
暴れる準備は決まって
The preparation to run wild is set,
派手なイントロダクション 唸った
and the flashy introduction roared.
有名なパーティーが始まった
The famous party has begun!
悪漢どもの番 また Bam Bam Bam
It's the villains' turn, again, Bam Bam Bam!
うるさい 面倒くさい 奴も あいやいやいや
Loud, annoying guys, ai-ya-ya-ya!
悪漢どもの番 また Bam Bam Bam
It's the villains' turn, again, Bam Bam Bam!
こりゃ痛い 関わんないよ だるいだけ
This hurts, I won't get involved, it's just tiresome.
揺れる揺れるシンギング
Swaying, swaying, singing!
圧倒的な宣言
An overwhelming declaration!
まだまだ踊ってよご三唱
Keep on dancing, sing three cheers!
揺れる揺れるシンギング
Swaying, swaying, singing!
圧倒的な宣言
An overwhelming declaration!
タラタタ タラタタ タララララ
Tara-tata, tara-tata, tara-ra-ra-ra!
清廉潔白 私の過去には何の過ちもございません
Pure and innocent, there are no mistakes in my past.
分厚くなってくルールブック
The rulebook keeps getting thicker,
見逃した時にはパンクス
and when you miss it, punks...
びっくり精度のサーチライト
A searchlight with surprising accuracy.
それはヤバいよ が一番怖いよ
“That's bad” is the scariest thing to hear.
レッドもイエローも関係ないのよ
Red or yellow doesn't matter,
一発退場
it's an instant ejection!
はい お疲れさん
Yes, thanks for your hard work.
1 2 3からカウンター
Counter from 1, 2, 3,
熱いロックンロールを食らった
I took a hit of hot rock 'n' roll.
インターバルにのぼせるウィナー
A winner getting dizzy during the interval,
番外のゾンビもバラバラ
the zombies outside the ranks are also in pieces.
アイドルタイムも終わって
The idle time is also over,
あっという間にここから終盤だぞ
and in a flash, it's the endgame from here!
ゾンビもネックも酸素欲しがって 踊るだけ
Zombies and necks both craving oxygen, just dancing.
悪漢どもの番 また Bam Bam Bam
It's the villains' turn, again, Bam Bam Bam!
うるさい 面倒くさい 奴も あいやいやいや
Loud, annoying guys, ai-ya-ya-ya!
悪漢どもの番 また Bam Bam Bam
It's the villains' turn, again, Bam Bam Bam!
こりゃ痛い 関わんないよ だるいだけ
This hurts, I won't get involved, it's just tiresome.
揺れる揺れるシンギング
Swaying, swaying, singing!
圧倒的な宣言
An overwhelming declaration!
まだまだ踊ってよご三唱
Keep on dancing, sing three cheers!
揺れる揺れるシンギング
Swaying, swaying, singing!
圧倒的な宣言
An overwhelming declaration!
タラタタ タラタタ タララララ
Tara-tata, tara-tata, tara-ra-ra-ra!
まだまだ暴れるが
I will still run wild,
Bam Bam Bam 死なないで
Bam Bam Bam, please don't die.
ラッタッタッタラ
Rat-tat-tat-tara!
OFFSIDE
作詞・作曲：マサ
Lyrics & Composition: Masa
ラッタッタッタラ
Rat-tat-tat-tara!
なんだか忙しない 笑うタイム
Somehow a busy laughing time,
ちぐはぐでバラバラ
incoherent and in pieces.
暴れたゾンビとロックスター
A raging zombie and a rock star,
飛んでったシガレット
a cigarette flying away.
空から撃ち抜くバニガ
A bunny girl shooting from the sky,
騒いでる様々
various people making a fuss.
現れた緊張のバランサー
The tension balancer that appeared,
笑ったか緊張とスーサイド うっさいな
did you laugh, tension and suicide? Shut up.
この山頂をたどって
Following this mountaintop,
まだまだいけるか
can we still keep going?
...ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
...The happy ending chime
想像通りじゃないなら
If it's not as imagined
塗り替えてしまうのさ
I will repaint it completely
揺れる 揺れる 揺れる 揺れる どうぞ
Swaying, swaying, swaying, swaying... Here you go
這い上がる態度は
The attitude of crawling up
分かち合うもんではないから
Isn't something to be shared
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
Kick it away and try dyeing it
そんなもんさ
That's how it is
正直こんなの 意味あるのかって
Honestly, wondering if this even has any meaning...
考えたところで 堂々巡りで
Even if I think about it, I'm just going in circles
あれもこれもそれも気になる
I'm curious about that, this, and everything else
気になる 気になる
Curious, so curious
それそれ願う 正義が絡み合う
Each wished-for justice becomes entangled
ああ まだまだいけそうだ
Ah, looks like I can still keep going
ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
The happy ending chime
想像通りじゃないなら
If it's not as imagined
塗り替えてしまうのさ
I will repaint it completely
揺れる 揺れる 揺れる 揺れる どうぞ
Swaying, swaying, swaying, swaying... Here you go
はい上がる態度は
The attitude of crawling up
分かち合うもんではないから
Isn't something to be shared
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
Kick it away and try dyeing it
そんなもんさ
That's how it is
どこで何が起きるか分からない
You never know what will happen where
まだやり直せるかな
I wonder if I can still start over
ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
The happy ending chime
想像通りじゃないなら
If it's not as imagined
塗り替えてしまうのさ
I will repaint it completely
揺れる 揺れる 揺れる 揺れる どうぞ
Swaying, swaying, swaying, swaying... Here you go
はい上がる態度は
The attitude of crawling up
分かち合うもんではないから
Isn't something to be shared
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
Kick it away and try dyeing it
そんなもんさ
That's how it is
はあ～い、よいしょ
Whew, alright...
やったー！こんちこはー！
Hooray! Hello everyone!
初めての生誕祭来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my very first birthday festival!
奏はしの、ついに活動1周年、生誕祭2025です！
I, Kanade Hashino, am finally celebrating my 1st anniversary and my 2025 Birthday Festival!
たくさんポストしてくれたら嬉しい！
I'd be so happy if you posted a lot!
あの、トレンド入っちゃう？
Like, maybe we'll get trending?
え、ありがとうございます、嬉しい！
Oh, thank you so much, I'm so happy!
これからも、あの、すっごいいろんな、初めてをお届けするので、ぜひポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I will continue to deliver many different firsts, so please post about it!
えー、先ほどは『神様』と『OFFSIDE』という曲を聴いていただきました
So, just now you listened to 'Kamisama' and 'OFFSIDE'.
どうですか？かっこよかったですか？
How was it? Was it cool?
かっこよかったよ～
It was so cool~
ありがと、ありがとね！初めての曲もね、この振り付けもめちゃくちゃ大好きなので、めちゃくちゃ披露できて嬉しいです！
Thank you! I love both my first songs and this choreography so much, so I'm thrilled to perform them!
この後も、まだたくさんあるので、一緒に楽しんでください！
There is still plenty more to come, so let's enjoy it together!
次は、今はかっこよかったけど、もっとバラエティパートです！
Next up... that was cool, but now we're moving on to the variety segment!
うおー、それでは、いきましょう！
Whoa! Well then, let's go!
One, two, one...
あっという間の綱渡り
In the blink of an eye, a tightrope walk
崩して落としてどうしたい？
Ruining it, dropping it, what do you want to do?
肝心なのはストレートなマインド
The most important thing is a straight mind
出し抜いて さぁ這い上がる
Outsmart them and crawl back up
行き着く先はヘブン or ヘル
The destination is heaven or hell
この世界のルール
The rules of this world
たった一つ 勝者こそが正義
There is only one: the victor is justice
女は度胸
A woman needs courage
焦らさせるのあいつを
I'll make him feel impatient
やれること何だってやる
I'll do whatever it takes
私は賭け狂いのクイーン
I am the compulsive gambling queen
お見通しよあんたの企み
I see right through your scheme
読みきって見せるわ
I'll read your mind completely
全部全部見透かして
Seeing through absolutely everything
私のものにする
I will make it all mine
あなたの髪の1本まで全部
Down to every single strand of your hair
覚悟決めて
Make up your mind,
震えた手振れ my heart
and steady your trembling hand, my heart.
欲しがる 容赦ない my baby
You're greedy and merciless, my baby.
誰にも負けない感じさせてよ my honey
Show me that you won't lose to anyone, my honey.
あわただしいショーだわ
It's a hectic show.
ほら 見せてあげる
Here, I'll show you.
秘密って甘いの
Secrets are sweet,
仕掛けて罠にはめるわ
I'll set one up and trap you.
油断誘うのよ
I will lure you into letting your guard down.
呼吸を止めたら じえんど
Once you stop breathing, it's the end.
何も知らないような顔で
With a face that knows nothing,
落とすわ あなたを
I'll bring you down.
気絶するほどにヨダレまみれ
Drooling so much you could faint,
読み切って連勝だ
read it all and win a streak.
ディーラーさん 手元見せないで
Mr. Dealer, don't show your hand.
どんな小さなズレだって
No matter how small a slip,
私の目は誤魔化されないわ
you can't deceive my eyes.
カメレオンみたいにセルフで
Like a chameleon, all by myself,
勝って 胃袋まで
I'll win all the way to your stomach,
愛し尽くしてあげる
and love you to death.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
The prey I target will never escape.
唇濡らしていただくわ my babe
I'll wet my lips and devour you, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで照らそう
Let's light things up with the Jack of Diamonds.
笑みを殺し待つだけ
I'll just kill my smile and wait.
私のポーカーフェイスは is perfect
My poker face is perfect.
一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
I won't show even a fraction of a gap.
視線感じてるわ
I can feel your gaze on me.
お望みは 最後まで
Your desires, to the very end...
見つめてばかり ヒラヒラで
Just staring and fluttering around,
愛しとしていかない日に
on days when I can't love you...
負けるのが怖いのはイージーゲーム
Being afraid to lose is an easy game.
読み切って連勝だ
Read it all and win a streak.
ディーラーさん 見透かして
Mr. Dealer, see right through me,
私のものにする
and make it mine.
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
Every single strand of your hair, everything...
カメレオンみたいにセルフで
Like a chameleon, all by myself...
震えているわよ my boy
You're trembling, my boy.
どこまで行くわよ
I'll go anywhere.
ディーラーさん テンプテーション
Mr. Dealer, temptation...
堪らないわ スリル
I can't resist the thrill.
誰にも触らせない このマネー
I won't let anyone touch this money.
カメレオンみたいにセルフで
Like a chameleon, all by myself...
さあ、覚悟決めて
Now, make up your mind,
灰になるまで踊って
and dance until you turn to ash.
欲しがる 容赦ない my baby
You're greedy and merciless, my baby.
誰にも負けない感じさせてよ my honey
Show me that you won't lose to anyone, my honey.
丸ノ内サディスティック
[Song: Marunouchi Sadistic]
報酬は入社後 並行線で
The reward after joining is on a parallel line,
東京は愛せど 何もない
Though I love Tokyo, there is nothing here.
リッケン620頂戴
Give me a Rickenbacker 620,
19万も持って居ない 御茶ノ水
I don't even have 190,000 yen in Ochanomizu.
マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
It's crazy getting high off the smell of a Marshall,
毎晩絶頂に達しているだけ
I'm just reaching a climax every night.
ラット１つを商売道具にしているさ
I use a single RAT pedal as my tool of the trade,
そしたらベンジーが肺に写ってトリップ
and then Benjie is projected onto my lungs and I trip.
警官ごっこ国境は越えても
Playing cop, even if we cross the border,
乗車必死
boarding is desperate.
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt.
税理士は雇って
Please hire a tax accountant,
頂戴 こりゃあ食う
oh, I'll devour this!
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk and marry me in the future.
毎晩寝具で遊戯するだけ
Just playing in bed every night...
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to try being a pizza delivery guy's girlfriend,
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
then Benjie, beat me with your Gretsch.
青噛んで行って頂戴
Please go on biting the blue,
終電で帰るってば、池袋
I told you I'd take the last train back to Ikebukuro.
Marshallの背後 飛んじゃって大変さ
Flying behind the Marshall amp, it's crazy.
毎晩絶頂に達しているだけ
Just reaching climax every night...
ラット一つを商売道具にしているさ
Using just a single RAT as my tool of the trade,
そしたらベンジー、肺に映ってトリップ
then Benjie, reflect in my lungs and trip me out.
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk and marry me in the future.
毎晩寝具で遊戯するだけ
Just playing in bed every night...
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to try being a pizza delivery guy's girlfriend,
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
then Benjie, beat me with your Gretsch.
はい！ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much!
次は、ゲストパートです！
Next is the guest part!
うわー！いくぞー！
Whoa! Let's go!
今日も元気にドカンを決めたら ヨーラン背負ってリーゼント
Once I style my trousers properly today too, I'll put on my coat and do my pompadour!
ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll, Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
ソリも入れたし 弁当も持ったし
Shaved my temples and packed my lunch!
可愛いあの娘はクルクルパーマに 長めのスカート引きずって
That cute girl has tight curls, dragging her long skirt on the ground!
ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll, Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
お手手つないで駅までしあわせ
Holding hands on the way to the station, we're so happy!
駅についたらドッパイ兄ちゃんと ガンのくれ合い飛ばし合い
When we get to the station, we exchange glares with a scary-looking guy!
ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll, Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
タイマンはりましょ 赤テープ同士で
Let's settle this one-on-one, red tape delinquent style!
おいくよー！
Here we go!
かあちゃん、そんなに心配すんなよ
Mom, don't worry so much.
勉強嫌いな俺だけどさ、人にはそれぞれ合った道ってもんがあんだよ
I hate studying, but everyone has a path that's right for them.
もっと大きな愛で、今の僕を包んでおくれよな
Please embrace who I am now with a bigger love.
なんだよ、彼女？あそこにマブいオンナがいるじゃんよー
What, a girlfriend? Look, there's a totally hot chick over there!
ダサい男連れてんな。おや？ラデンじゃない？
She's with a dorky guy. Wait, isn't that Raden?
電車に乗ったら便所に駆け込み 一駅だけのはっぴいタイム
Jumping into the train bathroom, a one-station-long happy time!
ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll, Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
火のないところに煙を立てて
Making smoke where there is no fire!
電車を飛び降り改札抜けたら 学校までは猛ダッシュ
Jumping off the train, through the ticket gate, sprinting to school!
ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll ツッパリHigh School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll, Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
またまた遅刻で今日も呼び出し
Late yet again, summoned to the office today too!
オッケーじゃん！
That's totally okay!
サンキュー！来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you! Thanks for coming!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
バレル！
[Title: Bareru!]
Uh, yeah 実を言うと待ってない 何事も
Uh, yeah, to be honest, I'm not waiting for anything.
平らになだらかに曲がり角へ
Smoothly, gently, towards the bend.
Uh, yeah どこにも見当たらない 人の足跡
Uh, yeah, nowhere to be found, are human footprints.
胸の高鳴りを抑え 送り込む肺に酸素 また震え
Suppressing my heart's pounding, sending oxygen to my lungs, trembling again,
灰色の山椒魚 アイロニーの夜明け
a gray salamander, the dawn of irony.
Who's next? 次は誰が描き出す画期的な地上絵
Who's next? Who's going to draw the next revolutionary geoglyph?
数千 of 屍を掻き分け誰もが血眼
Pushing through thousands of corpses, everyone is bloodshot-eyed.
上も下もパンパンな マキャベリ的な地獄から吸い上げる
Sucking it up from a hell packed tight, top and bottom, like a Machiavellian purgatory,
1000、孤独、現れ見せつける研いだ力を
a thousand solitudes, appearing to show off their honed power.
研ぎ澄まされたその刃で シャマランよろしく首突いて
With that sharpened blade, sticking your neck in like Shyamalan,
白熱の内側へ 百戦錬磨の呼び声
into the glowing inside, the call of a battle-tested veteran.
Uh, yeah えげつないもの発明したのかもな
Uh, yeah, I might have invented something nasty just now.
生中継 革命前夜 歓喜せよこのコラボ
Live broadcast on the eve of the revolution, rejoice at this collaboration.
バレる！この俺の天賦の才能がバレる！
It'll get exposed! This natural talent of mine will be exposed!
マジこれ面倒くさいな バレる！
Seriously, this is so troublesome, it'll get exposed!
バレる！バレる！世の中に気づかれる
It'll get exposed! It'll get exposed! Noticed by the world.
Let's get 追い風吹かせよ on my haters
Let's get... Blow a tailwind on my haters.
とりあえずはビル建てりゃ
For now, if I build a building,
ほら見たことかとにやけよう
let's smirk and say, "Look at that!"
ほら見たことかと にやけよう
Let's smirk and say, "Look at that!"
Uh, yeah 拍手と歓声 日の当たる場所
Uh, yeah, applause and cheers, a place in the sun.
沈着冷静 地に足をつけたままありがとう
Calm and cool-headed, keeping my feet on the ground, thank you.
知名度、名声は水物 勝ち馬乗らの拍手と
Fame and celebrity are volatile things, like the applause of bandwagoners.
頭で分かっちゃいるくせに体が求めてくミステリー
Even though I know it in my head, my body keeps seeking it, what a mystery.
化けの皮剥ぐから騒ぎ 息の根を抜く椅子取りゲーム
Much ado about stripping away the disguise, a life-and-death game of musical chairs.
ただ一度のミスが命取り みんな手のひら返して一斉に
Just one mistake is fatal, and everyone turns their backs all at once.
白黒つけられない もう捨て身、野次はいらない
Can't make it black and white, already desperate, no need for heckling.
いや失うものが何もない 何もない 何もない 何もない
No, there's nothing, nothing, nothing, nothing to lose.
俺を分かってくれと叫べ 世にしらしめたばかりに 自分をより自分らしく演じなきゃいけないハメに
Shouting "Understand me!", just because I made myself known to the world, I've ended up having to play myself even more like myself.
ボトムアップで得たあの味 でも俺はもうそこにはいない
That flavor obtained from bottom-up, but I'm no longer there.
俺って誰？俺って何？ビビって手も足も出ないで
Who am I? What am I? Being scared, unable to do anything.
バレる！俺にはもう何もない バレる！
It'll get exposed! I have nothing left anymore, it'll get exposed!
ハナから恥かいたって バレる！
Even if I'm embarrassed from the start, it'll get exposed!
バレる！バレる！化けの皮は剥がされる
It'll get exposed! It'll get exposed! The disguise will be stripped away.
Let's get 追い風吹かせよ on my haters
Let's get... Blow a tailwind on my haters.
手を叩いて指差して
Clapping hands and pointing fingers,
ほら見たことかと笑える
laughing and saying, "Look at that!"
ほら見たことかと 笑える
Laughing and saying, "Look at that!"
生きてる限りは勝ち逃げできねえな
As long as I'm alive, I can't just take the win and run.
衰え、錆び付き、どうかされてしまう定めか
Am I fated to decline, rust away, and be assimilated?
白旗を上げたのは
The one who raised the white flag,
唾を吐いたのは
the one who spat,
あの日の俺とよく似た目をしてた奴でした
was a guy with eyes just like mine back then.
あいにく俺はまだ渡らぬ三途の川
Unfortunately, I have yet to cross the Sanzu River.
今日もまた積み上げては蹴飛ばされる賽の河原
Today, once again, piling up stones only for them to be kicked down at Sai no Kawara.
挑み、顔を上げた、ニヤリと微笑んだ
Challenging, raised my face, and smirked.
知恵比べ 死のパズル 重ねる どっちを引いても仕組まれた
A battle of wits, a puzzle of death, stacking them up... Whichever I pull, it's rigged.
バレる！この俺の天賦の才能がバレる！
It'll get exposed! This natural talent of mine will be exposed!
マジこれ面倒くさいな バレる！
Seriously, this is so troublesome, it'll get exposed!
バレる！バレる！世の中に気づかれる
It'll get exposed! It'll get exposed! Noticed by the world.
Let's get 追い風吹かせよ on my haters
Let's get... Blow a tailwind on my haters.
とりあえずはビル建てりゃ
For now, if I build a building,
ほら見たことかとにやけよう
let's smirk and say, "Look at that!"
ほら見たことかと にやけよう
Let's smirk and say, "Look at that!"
あー！めっちゃありがとう！ありがとうー！
Ah! Thank you so much! Thank you!
お疲れ様！お疲れ！バイバイー！
Good job! Good job! Bye-bye!
こんちくわ！
Hello-chikuwa!
轟はじめ！
Todoroki Hajime!
こん！ちくわ！こん！こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa!
ぶんぶん！
Buzz buzz!
こん！ちくわ！こん！こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
こん！ちくわ！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Chikuwa!
ちゅっ！
Muah!
おっ おっ おっ ふーん
Oh, oh, oh, hmm.
泣いちゃうぞ ぴえんぴえん
I'm gonna cry, boohoo boohoo.
おっ おっ おっ うーん
Oh, oh, oh, hmm.
うーん す、す、す、すき
Hmm, h-h-h-I like you.
おっ おっ おっ ちゅっ！
Oh, oh, oh, muah!
泣いちゃうぞ ぴえん ぴえん
I'm gonna cry, boohoo boohoo.
泣いちゃうぞ
I'm gonna cry.
ごみゃん
Sowwy.
こん！ちくわ！こん！こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa!
最終手段 抱いてやる
Final resort, I'll hold you.
こん！ちくわ！こん！こんちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Hello-chikuwa!
こんちくわ！ちくわ！こーん！こん！こんちくわ！
Hello-chikuwa! Fish cake! Koon! Kon! Hello-chikuwa!
ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！
Pya! Pya! Pya! Pya!
あい！あい！あい！あい！
Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai!
カツオてき仮想敵？
Katsuo-like virtual enemy?
仮想... ああ、仮想敵か
Virtual... Ah, virtual enemy?
ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！ぴゃっ！
Pya! Pya! Pya! Pya!
あい！
Ai!
げんき！
Energetic!
泣かれたら 泣き返す 今を生きろよ！
If you cry, I'll cry back. Live in the present!
やさしいじゃん えー、抱くかあ
That's nice of you. Well, should I hold you?
こん！ちくわ！こん！こんちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Hello-chikuwa!
こんちくわ！こん！こん！こーん！こん！こんちくわ！
Hello-chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Koon! Kon! Hello-chikuwa!
こん！ちくわ！こん！こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
こん！ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa!
おわり！
The end!
わお！
Wow!
あのー、ノエル先輩がね
Um, Noel-senpai,
ラップしてたんだよねー
was rapping, you see,
ちょっと対抗してみようかな
so I thought I'd try to compete with her.
もうちょっと韻踏めない気するけど
I feel like I can't really rhyme that well though,
もう頭回んなくて
and my brain isn't working anymore.
よし、これで！
Alright, let's do this!
二日目！
Day two!
ノエルだんちょーに対抗！
Taking on Commander Noel!
対抗！
Taking on!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the rap boss!
ばんちょー！
Boss!
ラップでバトルしよーよー！
Let's do a rap battle!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the rap boss!
初テイムは ぷんぷんてんちょー
My first tame was the grumpy shop manager,
初レイドであっけなく終了
And my first raid ended so quickly.
その次テイムしたの アルゲンなんだよー！
The next one I tamed was an Argent!
ぷんげんぷんげん
Pungen, pungen!
トワさんとフブキさんで
With Towa-san and Fubuki-san,
大冒険だYO！
It's a grand adventure, YO!
ビーバーとっこう セメント大量！
Beaver rush, tons of cement!
大成功で おわっかYO！
A huge success, it's over, YO!
もっと強くなるばんちょー うぃあ
The boss is gonna get even stronger, we are...
あ！おい！ノエルお前負けてんぞ！
Ah! Hey! Noel, you're losing!
時間差がありすぎてラップできなかった、未熟者だよ
The time lag was too big so you couldn't rap! You're still a novice!
ちぇけちぇけ！
Check it, check it!
おい、やばい、やめてよ。日記でラップバトル始めないでよ。
Hey, wait, stop that. Don't start a rap battle with a diary entry.
全然いいけど
I mean, it's totally fine, but...
ラップバトルしよっかね
Let's do a rap battle!
二日目！
Day two!
ノエルだんちょーに対抗！
Taking on Commander Noel!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the rap boss!
ラップでバトルしよーよー！
Let's do a rap battle!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the rap boss!
初テイムは ぷんぷんてんちょー
My first tame was the grumpy shop manager,
初レイドであっけなく終了
And my first raid ended so quickly.
ちぇけちぇけ！
Check it, check it!
その次テイムしたの
The next one I tamed...
アルゲンなんだよー！
Was an Argent!
トワさんとフブキさんで
With Towa-san and Fubuki-san,
大冒険だYO！
It's a grand adventure, YO!
ビーバーとっこう セメント大量！
Beaver rush, tons of cement!
大成功で おわっかYO！
A huge success, it's over, YO!
もっと強くなるばんちょー
The boss is gonna get even stronger!
はい。番長の勝利、おめでとう！
Yes, victory goes to the boss! Congratulations!
ちぇけちぇけ！
Check it, check it!
I'm Koseki Bijou!
アイム 轟はじめ
I'm Todoroki Hajime!
Boom Boom Boom! Okay!
はじめまして
Nice to meet you!
きょうは いっしょに うたうー！ Let's go!
Today, let's sing together! Let's go!
Cool? Yeah! Thank you, thank you!
アイム ばんちょー Yeah!
I'm the boss, yeah!
We were cool, right? We were cool, okay?
ベリベリハッピー！ Thank you!
Very, very happy! Thank you!
Can you say something for me?
Sticking out your gyatt for Nerizzler
なに、なに、なに！？
What, what, what?!
You're so Bau Bau
You're so Biboo tax
I just wanna be your Shiori
Yeay! She said the thing!
Yay! She said the thing!
Sticking out your gyatt for Nerizzler
You're so Bau Bau
You're so Biboo tax
I just wanna be your Shiori
This one! This one! This one!
Wow wowow wha! Yeah!
Wow, wow, wow, yeah!
Are you ready? Okay!
Cool? Yeah! Thank you, thank you!
アイム ばんちょー Yeah!
I'm the boss, yeah!
We were cool, right? We were cool, okay?
ベリベリハッピー！ Thank you!
Very, very happy! Thank you!
I want to hear the word, Bijou senpai's 'Ryourya'.
I want to hear the word Bijou-senpai's "Ryourya"
はい？？
Huh??
頭痛くて、頭痛くてよーもう
My head hurts, my head really hurts...
ぼろぼろ
I'm a total mess...
いまフワモコが ばんちょー先生の所に向かってます！オーバー！
Fuwamoco is now heading towards Boss-sensei! Over!
ばんちょー先生だ、みゅはじめ！おな？
It's Boss-sensei, Myu Hajime! Right?
ばんちょー先生、いま持ってます。
Boss-sensei, we are holding you right now.
もたれてます
You are being held.
次はちょっとつめたいけど、がまんしてね！
The next part is a bit cold, so bear with it!
わ！つめたい！おへそにつめたーい！
Whoa! It's cold! Cold on my belly button!
OK、じゃあ、うん！
Okay then, yep!
次はハートマッサージね！
Next is a heart massage!
そう！ハートマッサージ？マッサージ！
Yes! Heart massage? Massage!
BAU BAU BAU BAU
おおかみ！だいじょうぶ！
Wolves! You're gonna be okay!
あいしりゅー！アイビリーブユー！
I love you! I believe you!
はあー！
Whew!
ばうばう！ばうばう！ばうばうソーセージ！
Bau bau! Bau bau! Bau bau sausage!
あたまがいたいよー
My head hurts...
せんぱい大丈夫になるからね！
Senpai, you'll be just fine!
これで大丈夫かなー！げんきになったー！
Is everything okay now? I'm all better!
ばうばうばう！これからも病院がんばろうねー！
Bau bau bau! Let's keep doing our best at the hospital!
うん！がんばろうねえ！
Yeah! Let's do our best!
ばうばう！
Bau bau!
殴り合いますか？
Shall we exchange blows?
あ、殴り合う？いいよ。ちょっと今、溜まってるわ。
Oh, punch each other? Sure. I have some pent-up energy right now.
溜まってるｗｗｗやめてｗｗｗ
Pent-up?! Stop, haha!
まあ久々にやるからね。ちょっとできるか...
Well, it's been a while. Let's see if we can do this...
イクゾッ！
Let's go!
ドドドドド！イヤー！
Dododododo! Yah!
あびゃびゃびゃびゃ
Abyabyabyabya!
負けねぇ！勝つ！やめろー！
I won't lose! I'll win! Stop it!
やめろー！
Stop it!
やめてー！
Stop!
イヤー！
No!
やめろー！イヤー！
Stop! No!
おれの勝ち！
I win!
完全勝利！
Complete victory!
ボール持って モチュッ
Hold the ball, *mochu*
ピュイ～ ホイッ
Pyui~ *hoi*
チョイチョイチョイ
Choi choi choi
ピュイ～ ホイッ
Pyui~ *hoi*
ボール持って モチュッ
Hold the ball, *mochu*
ピュイ～ ホイッ
Pyui~ *hoi*
Yes, I do.
ぶんぶんぶーん ぽんちょー
Boon boon boon, poncho
ぶんぶんぶんぶんぶーん
Boon boon boon boon boon
轟はじめです
I'm Hajime Todoroki.
またの名を ただの甘えん坊だ
Also known as just a spoiled brat.
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel.
またの名を 牛丼太郎だ
Also known as Gyudon Taro.
よろしくな
Nice to meet you!
やめろー！
Stop it!
やめてー！
Stop!
イヤー！
No!
イヤー！いやだー！
No! No!
負けられぬ！
I cannot lose!
ウオオ！
Uooo!
やめろー！
Stop it!
やめてー！
Stop!
イヤー！
No!
イヤー！いやだー！
No! No!
おれの勝ち！
I win!
完全勝利！
Complete victory!
なんなんだ このゲーム
What is this game?!
気合いじゃどうにもならんかったか
Guess guts couldn't save me...
あははは！
Ahahaha!
どうも もるでちおです
Hello, I'm Moldechio.
でび様に負けたので
Since I lost to Debi-sama,
今からでび様考案の うんちぷりぷりだんすをします
I'm now going to perform the Poop Pripri Dance created by Debi-sama.
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
どおだあ
How about that!
異界の扉 開かれ中 から来た 轟はじめ
From the opening gate to another world, I'm Hajime Todoroki.
またの名を はじはじはじめによろしく
Also known as Haji-haji-hajime, nice to meet you!
悪魔中から来た でびでび・でびる
From the devil world, I'm Debidebi Devil!
またの名を うんちうんちうんち
Also known as Poop Poop Poop!
うんち うんち
Poop, Poop
うんち王
Poop King
はじめまして
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして 来てくださって
Nice to meet you, thank you for coming.
じゃあ今度僕が踊ってって言ったら踊ってくれる？
Then, next time I say "dance", will you dance?
うんちぷりぷりだんす！
Poop Pripri Dance!
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha puryapuriya
うんちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うんちゃ
Uncha puryapuriya uncha
どおだあ
How about that!
またね
See you!
また遊んでください
Please play with me again!
また遊んでやるよ
I'll play with you again!
やったー！
Yay!
せーのっ
Ready, set...
おつもるでちおー！
Otsumoldechio~!
うわー、すごい楽しいコラボだった！
Wow, that was a super fun collab!
あれ？ちょ、カメラちゃん、こっちこっち、こっちこっち
Oh? Hey, camera-chan, over here, over here!
うわ、いやー、いや、すごい楽しかった！
Whoa, man, that was so much fun!
あと、トレンドも１位に入ったちゅうことで、これはなんなんですかね？ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Also, we hit #1 on trending, which is crazy! Thank you so much! Thank you!
えー、ReGLOSSのみんなと、えー、べーちゃんと、ぺこら先輩と、
Um, everyone from ReGLOSS, Bae-chan, Pekora-senpai,
ビジュ先輩と、フワモコ先輩と、ノエル先輩と、でびちゃん、というね、
Bijou-senpai, Fuwamoko-senpai, Noel-senpai, and Debi-chan—
豪華11名のゲストが来てくれました！嬉しい！
A gorgeous lineup of 11 guests came! I'm so happy!
あの最後のね、やつは、はじめのやる気出ないソングを作ってくれた、
For that last part, Otamayo-sensei, who made my "No Motivation Song",
おたまよ先生のこれまでの作品をメドレーにしてもらいました。可愛いメドレーありがとうございます！
put together a medley of their previous works. Thank you for the cute medley!
このメドレー以外にもね、いろんな作品作ってるので、ぜひいろいろ見てください。
Other than this medley, they've created many other works, so please go check them out!
もう本当に先輩も同期も、みんな来てくれて、にじさんじからでびちゃんもね、来てくれて、
Seriously, seniors and peers, everyone came, and even Debi-chan from Nijisanji came,
本当嬉しい！またコラボしてほしいなー！
I'm so happy! I hope we can collab again!
はい、ということで、いやー、
All right, so, yeah...
皆さん、どうですか？
Everyone, how do you like it?
お新衣装ですよ！いつも通り可愛いだろ？可愛いだろ？
It's a new outfit! It's cute as always, right? Cute, right?
ま、でもね、ちょっと、これからまたダンスを披露したいので、えっと、
Well, but, you see, I want to perform another dance after this, so, um,
ちょっとね、ダンスも見えやすいのにストレッチしてくるわ。ちょっと待ってて。ちょっと待ってて。
I'm going to stretch to make the dance easier to see. Wait a moment. Please wait a moment.
ボキボキ、うわー、体固くなってたわ。伸びた伸びた。
Crack, crack, wow, my body was so stiff. Stretched, stretched.
ということでね、次の曲行きたいと思います！
So, I'd like to move on to the next song!
聞いてください。ワールドイズマイン。
Please listen to... World is Mine.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そう言う熱い心経て
Through such a warm heart...
それ！
Let's go!
その一　いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Rule number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different.
その二　ちゃんと靴まで見ること　いいね？
Rule number two: Look closely all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三　私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Rule number three: Reply to my every word with three words.
わかったら右手がお留守なのを　何とかして！
If you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
キミに心から思ってほしいの「かわいい」って
I just want you to think I'm cute from the bottom of your heart.
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess in the world.
気がついて　ねえねえ　待たせるなんて論外よ
Notice me, hey, hey! Keeping me waiting is out of the question.
私を誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am anyway?
もう何だか　甘いものが食べたい！
Now I really want to eat something sweet!
いますぐによ
Right now!
あう！
Ow!
Check one, two!
う〜あ！
Woo-ah!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ　文句は許しませんの
My flaws? You must mean my cuteness. No complaints allowed!
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと……
Hey, are you listening to me? Excuse me...
あ、それとね　白いお馬さん　決まってるでしょ？迎えに来て
Oh, and about that white horse, it's a given, right? Come pick me up.
わかったらかしづいて手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, bow down, take my hand, and call me "Princess."
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね、少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit, okay?
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My one and only prince in the world.
気がついて　ほらほら　おててが空いてます
Notice me, look, look! My hand is empty.
無口でぶっきらぼうなおうじさま
My silent and blunt prince...
もうどうして！気がついてよ早く
Geez, why?! Notice me already!
あう！
Ow!
絶対キミはわかってない
You definitely don't get it...
わかってない……わー
You don't get it... waah!
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ　こだわりたまごの溶けるプリン
A strawberry shortcake and melt-in-your-mouth pudding made with select eggs...
みんな　みんな　我慢します……わがままな子だと思わないで
I'll hold back on all of them... so don't think of me as selfish.
私だってやればできるもん　あとで後悔するわよ
I can do it if I try, you know. You'll regret this later!
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
ちゃんと見ててよね　どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Keep your eyes on me, or I might go somewhere else!
不意に抱きしめられた　急にそんな　えっ？
Suddenly, you hugged me... out of nowhere, huh?
「轢かれる、危ないよ」そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
"You'll get hit, it's dangerous," you say as you look away.
……こっちのが危ないわよ
...It's much more dangerous like this.
あう！
Ow!
Hey baby!
あー！
Aaah!
街の明かりがにじんでる　そっと
The city lights are softly blurring...
手で触れそうな三日月
The crescent moon looks close enough to touch.
あなたに会える特別な……
A special day to meet you...
特別な日曜日
A special Sunday...
さっききらめくダイヤモンドで
shining just now like a diamond.
いつもよりゆっくり
Slower than usual,
いつもより早く
faster than usual...
一緒にいたくて
I wanted to be with you.
慣れないハイヒール よろめいちゃうから
Because I stumble in these unfamiliar high heels,
腕を貸して その手
lend me your arm, your hand.
見え見えかしら
Is it too obvious?
恋はイリュージョン 少しロマンチック
Love is an illusion, a little romantic.
予想できない トリック仕掛けて
Playing an unpredictable trick.
恋はイリュージョン 少しファンタスティック
Love is an illusion, a little fantastic.
隠しきれない この胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this throbbing in my chest.
瞳閉じてみたら
If I try closing my eyes,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ 聞こえてくるでしょ
you can hear the fizzing, right?
映画のワンシーンみたいに キュンとする
My heart flutters like a scene in a movie.
仕草リサーチしても
Even if I research how to act,
あなたに会った瞬間 全部曖昧
the moment I see you, it all becomes a blur.
揺れてるピンクサファイア
The swaying pink sapphire.
言葉より目と目で
With eyes rather than words,
目と目より心で
with the heart rather than eyes...
通じ合えたら
If only we could understand each other.
慣れない静けさに 緊張しちゃうから
Because I get nervous in this unfamiliar silence,
微笑んで見せて その手
show me a smile, your hand.
贅沢かしら
Is that too much to ask?
恋はイリュージョン 甘いテンプテーション
Love is an illusion, a sweet temptation.
予想できない トリック仕掛けて
Playing an unpredictable trick.
恋はイリュージョン 甘いテンプテーション
Love is an illusion, a sweet temptation.
隠しきれない この胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this throbbing in my chest.
シャンパンの泡のよう
Like champagne bubbles,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ 弾けているでしょ
they are bursting fizzy, right?
恋はイリュージョン すごいロマンチック
Love is an illusion, so romantic.
予想してない ふとした温もり
An unexpected, sudden warmth.
恋はイリュージョン かなりファンタスティック
Love is an illusion, quite fantastic.
隠しきれない この胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this throbbing in my chest.
瞳閉じてみたら
If I try closing my eyes,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ 聞こえてくるでしょ
you can hear the fizzing, right?
いつまで子供のままでいる？
"How long are you going to stay a kid?"
そんな言葉がふりかかる
Such words are showered upon me.
黙って見てればいいんだ
"You should just shut up and watch."
笑ってそう言ってやれ
Laugh and tell them that!
人生にはないんだ take 2
There is no "take 2" in life.
平凡でくだらない退屈
A mediocre, stupid, boring routine...
なんてごめんだ
...is something I want no part of.
現実的な言葉なんかには耳をふさげ
Block your ears to realistic words.
ネバーランドに閉じこもって
Lock yourself away in Neverland,
いつまでだって夢を語るんだ
and talk about your dreams forever.
笑う奴には唾を吐け
Spit on those who laugh at you.
にっちもさっちもいかない
Even when you're stuck in a dead-end,
綺麗事に踊り踊らされ
dancing and being danced by pretty words,
大人の言う常識なんてものは丸めて捨てちまえ
roll up and throw away common sense told by adults!
ピーターパン症候群と指をさされて罵られようが
Even if they point fingers and call you "Peter Pan Syndrome,"
おとぎ話みたいなハッピーエンドを思い描いて生きていくんだ
keep living while imagining a fairy-tale happy ending!
Wow...
こっち指差して笑ってんだろ
You're pointing over here and laughing, aren't you?
好きに笑えよ それで別にいいさ
Laugh all you want, that's fine by me.
お前なんかに そう お前らなんかに
To someone like you, yes, to people like you...
何も言われたくない 黙って見てろ
...I have nothing to say, just sit back and watch.
やり直しのきかない人生
A life that can't be redone,
一度でいいチャンスをください
please give me just one chance.
掴んで 離さない
I'll grab it and never let go,
もう俺のものなんだ
it's already mine.
ネバーランドの大気圏を
Breaking through the atmosphere of Neverland,
破って今 夢を叶えるんだ
I'll make my dream come true now!
笑う奴など 蹴り飛ばせ
Kick away anyone who laughs at you!
打ち手はない 残されてない？
No moves left? Nothing remaining?
ネガティブを押し付けてくんな
Don't force your negativity on me.
大人のあんたも知らない世界を
I am living in a world
俺は生きてるんだ
that even you, an adult, don't know!
ピーターパン症候群（シンドローム）と
Even if they think of it as Peter Pan Syndrome,
思われたって 馬鹿にされたって
or even if they make fun of me,
おとぎ話みたいな
Like a fairytale,
ハッピーエンドに一直線に進んでいくんだ
I'm heading straight for a happy ending!
夢の見過ぎと 馬鹿にされた少年が
The boy ridiculed for dreaming too much...
夢を掴む物語を
...will grasp his dreams and create a story...
見事な逆転劇をこの手で
...a brilliant turnaround with his own hands!
巻き起こせ
Let's make it happen!
見せつけろ
Show them all!
にっちもさっちもいかない？
Feeling completely stuck?
綺麗事に踊り踊らされ
Dancing to pretty words and sweet talk,
大人の言う常識なんてものは
all that common sense spouted by adults,
丸めて捨てちまえ
roll it up and throw it away!
ピーターパン症候群（シンドローム）と
Even if they point fingers at my Peter Pan Syndrome,
指をさされ 罵られようが
and hurl insults at me,
おとぎ話みたいなハッピーエンドを
like a fairytale,
そう自ら掴み取るんだ
I will grab that happy ending with my own hands!
Wow...
はい、えー、可愛い、可愛い！ありがとうございます。
Yes, ah... "Cute, cute!" Thank you very much!
えー、初めてタップに挑戦しました。声はいい？了解ちゃん！
Ah, I challenged tap dancing for the first time. Is my voice good? Roger-chan!
そして、えー、初めての歌枠で歌った、はじめの、大好きな、えー、歌手の「ピーターパン」です。ありがとうございます。
And, ah, that was "Peter Pan" by my favorite singer, which I sang in my very first karaoke stream. Thank you very much!
えー、次は！オリ曲を2曲！やっていきます！
Next! I'll be performing two original songs!
え？オリ曲2曲？え？そんな持ってたっけ？とどろきはじめ。
Eh? Two original songs? Eh? Did Todoroki Hajime even have that many?
カウンタック、そして、新曲がでます！
Countach, and... a new song is coming!
えー、2曲続けて聞いてください。それでは聞いてください。「カウンタック」。
Please listen to these two songs back-to-back. Well then, here is "Countach".
何のために頑張るの？ 報われないって言ったって
What am I working so hard for? Even if they say it won't pay off,
結局、正直者が 道化師（ピエロ）で踊る残像
in the end, it's just an afterimage of the honest person dancing like a clown.
それ 賢く 生きてるあの子
That girl living so wisely...
懐に舞い込む 優待は正義でしょ
...getting special treatment in her pocket, that's justice, right?
アブラカタブラ 開けるよパンドラ
Abracadabra, I'll open Pandora's box.
抑えきれないのさ 歌うかカサンドラ
I can't hold it back, shall I sing, Cassandra?
6:00 PM（シックスピーエム）鳴るアラーム 暴れる猛るカニバル
At 6:00 PM, the alarm rings; a wild, raging carnival.
Everybody gonna put your hands, clap! clap! まだ見ぬ世界 飛び込み 3, 2, 1!
Everybody, put your hands up, clap, clap! Dive into an unseen world, 3, 2, 1!
上がれ感情（テンション） 体揺らして
Let your emotions rise, sway your body!
ほら 規制（きせい）ない あるがままぶち壊せ
See, there are no regulations! Break it down just as you are!
上がれ感情（テンション） 体揺らして
Let your emotions rise, sway your body!
ほら 規制（きせい）ない あるがままぶち壊せ
See, there are no regulations! Break it down just as you are!
カウンタック 最上級のカウンタック
Countach! The supreme Countach!
カウンタック 一心不乱でカウンタック
Countach! Wholeheartedly, Countach!
カウンタック ヒント等（ら）のカウンタック
Countach! Countach of hints and such!
カウンタック 何度だってカウンタック
Countach! Countach over and over again!
息を潜めて自分を 殺すのはもう慣れてるの
I'm already used to holding my breath and killing myself.
存在価値 存在証明なんて どうでもいいわ
Value of existence, proof of existence... I don't care about any of that.
宴（うたげ）ならエンドレス 今宵取っ払う フェイズからボーダーレス
If it's a banquet, it's endless; tonight we strip it away, borderless from this phase.
熱視（ねっし）の雷（いかづち）浴びてパーフェクト 弾けて飛んでリセット
Showered in the lightning of passionate gazes, perfect! Burst open, fly high, and reset!
アブラカタブラ 開けるよパンドラ
Abracadabra, I'll open Pandora's box.
抑えきれないのさ
I can't hold it back...
轟くサンダー
Todoroku thunder...
本性はカモフラージュ 本能だけで十分 混ざり合う
Our true nature is camouflaged, instinct alone is enough to mingle together.
Everybody gonna put your hands clap clap
Everybody's gonna clap their hands, clap, clap!
明日のことは忘れろ 3, 2, 1
Forget about tomorrow! 3, 2, 1!
叫べてっぺんへ 声を枯らして
Scream to the very top, until you lose your voice!
君だけの人生 楽しまなきゃ損じゃない
It's your one and only life, if you don't enjoy it, it's a waste!
叫べてっぺんへ 声を枯らして
Scream to the very top, until you lose your voice!
君だけの人生 楽しまなきゃ損じゃない
It's your one and only life, if you don't enjoy it, it's a waste!
6 PM 鳴るアラーム 暴れるまでクールにカーニバル
The alarm rings at 6 PM, keep it cool until we run wild at the carnival!
Everybody gonna put your hands clap clap
Everybody's gonna clap their hands, clap, clap!
まだ見ぬステージへ飛び込め 3, 2, 1
Dive into an unseen stage! 3, 2, 1!
Are you ready?
焦がれた感情へ 体揺らして
Shake your body to your yearning emotions!
ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
Look, just smash those preconceptions as you are!
焦がれた感情へ 体揺らして
Shake your body to your yearning emotions!
ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
Look, just smash those preconceptions as you are!
Countach 最上級の Countach
Countach, the highest-grade Countach!
Countach 一心不乱で Countach
Countach, with single-minded devotion, Countach!
It's your Countach
Countach 何度だって Countach
Countach, over and over again, Countach!
バンザイ 無能な命に
Banzai to this incompetent life!
くだらないよ 紛い物だって
It's worthless, even if it's a counterfeit...
ラリアッチュー
Lariat-chuu!
BANZAI 作詞・作曲：マサ 編曲：田中タツヤ
BANZAI (Lyrics/Composition: Masa, Arrangement: Tatsuya Tanaka)
漠然息してるようもん
I'm just vaguely breathing anyway.
不条理ふみながら僕はハァン
Stepping over absurdity, I sigh...
才華はゼロ
My talent is zero,
どうにかなりやがっちゃってキャラ
somehow managing with this character...
歓声はノー
the cheers are nonexistent,
だっての
that's how it is.
愛にもたれた言葉で心拍数
My heart rate goes up from words leaning on love,
生きてく程胸は沈んでく
the more I live, the heavier my chest sinks.
どうしてんだろうな？
What's going on with me?
この脳が揺れるの
My brain is shaking...
かいつまんでもしょうがねぇ
There's no point in summarizing it,
汗かき稼ぐお金はどんだけ？
how much money do I even make sweating away?
ああだこうだ
Saying this and that,
そんなもんか
is that all it is?
五月蝿えわな
It's so annoying.
バンザイ 無能な命に
Banzai to this incompetent life!
から回ってく脳を満たしてくれ
Fill up my brain that's spinning out of control!
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't draw any vision of the future,
くだらないよ 紛い物だってそれ
it's worthless, even if it's just a counterfeit.
半端者なら 寄る辺なき nutty tune
If you're a half-baked person, with no shelter, a nutty tune!
朱色になって僕は思い通り
Turning crimson, I'll have it my way!
太陽系で巣食った 罵詈雑言インベーダー
An abusive invader nesting in the solar system,
足が止まってるシューゲイザー
a shoegazer whose feet have stopped,
死にそうでもギリですか？
are you barely holding on even if you feel like dying?
のらりくらり躱すわ
I'll dodge it lazily,
はじめまして神様
nice to meet you, God.
もし救われるのなら
If I'm to be saved,
裏切るわ今から
I'll betray you from now on.
get down get down 揺らめく
get down, get down, swaying,
get down get down 飲み込んだ
get down, get down, swallowed it down.
フィードバックが
The feedback...
君を狂わしてんだ
is driving you crazy!
滅多なもんじゃ驚かねぇ
I won't be easily surprised,
汗かき生きた最後もあっけねぇ
the end of a life spent sweating is so anticlimactic.
なんだかんだ
One way or another,
そんなもんさ
that's just how it is.
虚しいわな
It's empty, isn't it?
バンザイ 無能な命に
Banzai to this incompetent life!
から回ってく脳を満たしてくれ
Fill up my brain that's spinning out of control!
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't draw any vision of the future,
くだらないよ 紛い物だってそれ
it's worthless, even if it's just a counterfeit.
半端者なら 寄る辺なき nutty tune
If you're a half-baked person, with no shelter, a nutty tune!
朱色になって僕は思い通り
Turning crimson, I'll have it my way!
はい！ということで、グッズ発表にいきます！
Alright! So, I'm going to announce the merch!
轟はじめ誕生日記念2025
Todoroki Hajime Birthday Celebration 2025...
フルセットはこんな感じです！
...the full set looks like this!
1つずつ紹介していきます！
I'll introduce them one by one!
1つ目、アクリルパネル！
First, the Acrylic Panel!
おむちちゃうだーちゃんの可愛いイラストと
With Omuti Chowder-chan's cute illustration...
こちらオーロラ加工になってます！
...and it has an aurora finish!
はじめが、ジャケットを試着しているような、めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It looks like Hajime is trying on the jacket. It's so cute!
2つ目！BANCHOアクリルキーホルダー！
Second! BANCHO Acrylic Key Holder!
おむちちゃうだーちゃんの、ぼんぼん、BANCHOのイラストです！
It features Omuti Chowder-chan's BmBm BANCHO illustration!
3つつなげても、1つずつでも使えます！
You can connect all three, or use them individually!
カラビナはイカツい形になってます。ぜひカバンとかにつけてみてね！
The carabiner is a cool design. Please attach it to your bag!
3つ目！BANCHOナイロンジャケット！
Third! BANCHO Nylon Jacket!
こちらは実際に実物で色味をチェックして使いやすいデザインにしました！
We checked the colors in person to make it easy to wear!
おむちちゃうだーちゃんのミニBANCHOのイラストと、表にははじめの考えたBANCHOのロゴがついてます！
It has mini BANCHO illustration, and Hajime's custom logo on the front!
チャック、イカツい形になってます。キービジュアルのはじめとお揃いのデザインです！
The zipper is in a cool shape. It matches Hajime's design on the key visual!
最後！シチュエーションボイス！「しみらーるっく」
Lastly! Situation Voice! "Similar Look"
ナイロンジャケットにまつわるボイスです。よかったら合わせて聴いてください！
It's a voice pack related to the jacket. Please listen to it!
今回、フルセット購入特典は2つあります！
There are two bonuses for purchasing the full set!
1つ目！直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
First! Hand-signed Instax-style bromoid card!
あ、数量限定になってます！
Ah, it's limited in quantity!
このライブが良かったなと思ってくださったら、次回以降のライブの励みになるので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
If you enjoyed this live, please support me as it motivates future shows!
2つ目！
Second!
オフィシャルショップにて購入した方限定で、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使えるカードが1枚つきます！
If you buy from the official shop, you'll get a hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME card!
カードの詳細や遊び方については公式ホームページを見てください！
Please check the official website for card details!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！いっきっちゃう！
That's all for the merch! Let's keep going!
あ、まだ、まだまだ踊っていくので、ぜひ最後まで見てください！
I'm still going to keep on dancing, so please watch until the end!
それでは、いけ！はじめダンサーズ、いくよ！
Alright, let's go! Hajime Dancers, here we go!
あ、見えた！こっちも！
Ah, I see you! This side too!
あ、こっちの皆さんも！こっちも！
Everyone over here too! Over here too!
はい、クラップ！
Alright, clap!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
本当に本当にライブ来てくれて、ありがとうね！
Thank you so much for coming to the live stream!
はい！ということで、みなちゃん本当にありがとうございました！
Alright! Thank you so much, everyone!
えー、このあと、21時新曲「BANCHO」のMVプレミアム公開、そしてグッズ販売も開始されます！
At 21:00, the new song "BANCHO" MV premiers, and merch sales start!
そしてそのあとは、メンバー限定のアンコールライブもあります！
And after that, there's a member-exclusive encore live!
うわぁ、時間ぴったり！うれしい！
Wow, perfect timing! I'm so happy!
あの、トレンドもね、ありがとうございます！本当にみんなありがとう！
Also, thank you for making it trend! Thank you so much!
本当にありがとう！バイバイ！
Thank you so much! Bye-bye!
FIRST STARRING ROLE / TODOROKI HAJIME BIRTHDAY LIVE 2025
みなたん!! いつも応援ありがとう!!
Everyone!! Thank you as always for your support!!
ずっと夢だったソロLIVEができて本当に幸せです！
I'm so happy to have been able to perform my dream solo live!
次のステージではもっとパワーアップして、
For the next stage, I will power up even more,
何回も何回も組員を悶絶させるマッ!!
and make the crew members swoon again and again, ma!!
【重大告知】 revolution
[Major Announcement] revolution